CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY TRIMARK HOME VIDEO
[ LOUD HISSING ]
UHH ...
[ HOLLOW ECHOING ]
[ SCRAPING ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
[ ECHOING CLANG ]
UHH !
[ LABORED BREATHING ]
HEY .
AAAHHH !
AAH !
I 'M SORRY .
IT 'S ALL RIGHT . I 'M NOT GONNA HURT YOU .
WHAT DO YOU WANT ? !
I THOUGHT YOU WERE ...
WHAT ? !
I DON 'T KNOW .
[ LOW MECHANICAL HUM ]
[ RUMBLING ]
Woman : HELP !
HELP !
STOP !
Woman : WHAT ?
WHAT ?
[ WHISPERING ] It 's OK .
Come here .
IT 'S OK . CALM DOWN .
EVERYTHING 'S GONNA BE FINE .
WHAT WAS IN THERE ?
JUST GIVE ME A MINUTE TO FIGURE THINGS OUT .
WHY ARE YOU AFRAID OF THAT ROOM ? !
GIVE ME A MINUTE , I SAID !
[ LOUD SLIDING ]
HOW MANY PEOPLE ARE IN THIS THING ?
LISTEN ! WE CAN 'T GO CLIMBING AROUND IN HERE .
WHY NOT ? [ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
There 's traps .
WHAT DO YOU MEAN , TRAPS ?
BOOBY TRAPS . I LOOKED IN A ROOM DOWN THERE ,
AND SOMETHING ALMOST CUT MY HEAD OFF .
OHH ...
OHH !
Woman : HOLY CATS !
HOLY , HOLY CATS .
ARE YOU ALL RIGHT ?
MISTER .
WORTH !
DON 'T WORRY .
I HIT MY HEAD .
LET ME TAKE A LOOK AT THAT . IT 'S OK .
I 'M A DOCTOR . DOESN 'T LOOK BAD .
WHAT THE HELL ARE YOU DOING ?
[ HIGH-PITCHED WHISTLE ]
HEY , OLD MAN . DID YOU HEAR WHAT I SAID ?
[ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
MOTION DETECTORS
INTEGRATED INTO THE WALLS .
TOUGH TO SPOT .
Woman : OH , GOD .
[ SOBBING ] OH , GOD , OH , GOD !
WAIT A SECOND .
LET 'S ALL JUST RELAX FOR A MINUTE .
DOES ANYBODY REMEMBER HOW THEY GOT HERE ?
PEROGIES !
I WAS EATING DINNER .
PEROGIES . CHEESE AND POTATO .
I RAN OUT OF SOUR CREAM ,
AND THEN I WENT TO THE FRIDGE , AND THEN - -
I DON 'T KNOW .
YOU ?
LEAVEN ?
I ...
I JUST WENT TO BED , AND ...
WHAT ABOUT YOU ?
I JUST WOKE UP HERE .
MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT .
IT 'S LIKE CHILE . THEY ALWAYS COME
IN THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT .
WHO ?
ONLY THE GOVERNMENT COULD BUILD SOMETHING THIS UGLY .
OH , IT AIN 'T GOVERNMENT .
THEN WHAT IS IT ?
I DON 'T KNOW . [ RUMBLING ]
ALIENS .
PLEASE . WE 'RE SPOOKED ENOUGH AS IT IS .
LET 'S ... LET 'S RULE OUT ALIENS FOR NOW
AND CONCENTRATE ON WHAT WE KNOW .
MY MOM 'S GONNA FREAK .
RENNES ?
I JUST WON 'T BE THERE . THEY 'LL FREAK .
WHAT DO YOU THINK , RENNES ?
WE WON 'T SOLVE JACK SHIT SITTIN ' STILL .
I 'M MOVIN ' IN A STRAIGHT LINE TILL I GET TO THE END .
ALL RIGHT . I TEND TO AGREE .
Woman : SHOULDN 'T WE WAIT HERE ?
FOR WHAT ?
TO SEE IF ANYBODY COMES ?
NO ONE 'S GONNA COME .
LOOK . THERE 'S A WAY IN HERE ,
SO THERE 'S GOTTA BE A WAY OUT .
WE CAN AVOID THE TRAPS USING THE BOOT .
HOLLOWAY , IS IT ? WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
LOOK FOR AN EXIT ?
OK .
WHAT ABOUT YOU ?
CAN 'T BE THAT SIMPLE .
Rennes : IT WON 'T BE THAT SIMPLE .
LOOK AROUND .
TAKE A GOOD , LONG LOOK-SEE .
' CAUSE I GOT A FEELIN ' IT 'S LOOKIN ' AT US .
I JUST WANT TO WAKE UP .
LEAVEN .
WE CAN DO THIS .
WE JUST HAVE TO STAY CALM
AND WORK TOGETHER AS A TEAM .
URRHH !
THERE 'S GONNA BE A LOT OF PEOPLE
LOOKIN ' FOR US ON THE OUTSIDE .
I 'M A COP . ALL RIGHT ?
YOU 'RE A COP ? YEAH .
I 'M GONNA GET YOU OUTTA HERE .
I PROMISE .
YOU GOTTA BE WITH ME ON THIS ONE .
OK .
[ DOOR SLIDES OPEN ]
BOOT IT .
CLEAN .
[ DOOR SLIDING OPEN ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ RATTLING ]
OH ...
Holloway : THAT ONE SOUNDED CLOSER .
IT 'S MECHANICAL .
SEEMS TO COME AT REGULAR INTERVALS .
Quentin : MAYBE IT 'S THE VENTILATION SYSTEM .
Rennes : NO VENTS .
Holloway : NO KIDDING . I 'M BOILING .
WHAT IS IT ?
SERIAL NUMBERS ?
Holloway : ROOM NUMBERS .
THEY 'RE DIFFERENT IN EACH ROOM .
OH , GREAT . WELL , THERE 'S ONLY 566 MILLION ,
400 THOUSAND-ODD ROOMS IN THIS THING .
WELL , THERE BETTER NOT BE .
WE HAVE ABOUT 3 DAYS WITHOUT FOOD AND WATER
BEFORE WE 'RE TOO WEAK TO MOVE .
WELL , THEY HAVE TO FEED US , DON 'T THEY ?
HOLLOWAY .
Holloway : OH , WE HAVE HEAT , STRESS , PHYSICAL EXERTION ,
I.E. , DEHYDRATION ,
HEADACHES , DIZZINESS , DISORIENTATION ,
CONFUSED MENTAL PROCESSES .
THE BODY EVENTUALLY BEGINS TO BREAK DOWN ITS OWN TISSUE .
SUCK ON IT .
KEEPS THE SALIVA FLOWIN ' .
[ SNIFFING ]
WHAT ?
THE AIR SEEMS DRY IN THERE .
Holloway : TRAPPED ?
MOLECULAR CHEMICAL SENSOR .
WHY THE HELL DIDN 'T THE BOOT SET IT OFF ?
THE BOOT 'S NOT ALIVE . DETECTS HYDROGEN SULFIDE
EXCRETED FROM THE SKIN .
HOW IS IT YOU KNOW SO MUCH ABOUT SENSORS , RENNES ?
[ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
" RENN . "
NOT " RENNS . "
IT 'S FRENCH .
FINE . YOU 'RE FRENCH . I 'M ASKIN ' YOU HOW - -
RENNES .
SENSOR EXPERT .
ABOUT THE RIGHT AGE .
I DON 'T BELIEVE IT .
HA HA HA HA HA !
THIS GUY 'S THE " WREN . "
THE WHAT ?
HE 'S THE WREN . THE BIRD OF ATTICA .
FLEW THE COOP ON 6 MAJOR PRISONS .
7 .
Holloway : YOU 'RE KIDDING , RIGHT ?
YOU CAN GET US OUT .
MAYBE .
AN ESCAPE ARTIST .
YEAH . I 'M HARRY FUCKIN ' HOUDINI .
THE ONLY REASON I DRAGGED YOU THIS FAR
IS ' CAUSE I NEED YOUR BOOTS .
IF YOU DON 'T SMARTEN UP , I 'M GONE LIKE THAT .
NO MORE TALKIN ' .
NO MORE GUESSIN ' .
DON 'T EVEN THINK ABOUT NOTHIN '
THAT 'S NOT RIGHT IN FRONT OF YA .
THAT 'S THE REAL CHALLENGE .
YOU GOTTA SAVE YOURSELVES FROM YOURSELVES .
[ CLICK ]
MERDE .
[ BEEP BEEP ]
AAAHHH !
Rennes : AAH !
GET HIM OUT !
ARRGGHH ...
AAH ! AAH !
AAH ! ARRHH !
ARRHH ! ARRHH !
OHH ! UHH !
[ SCREAMING CONTINUES ]
[ SOBBING ]
[ SCREAMING AND SOBBING ]
OH , MY GOD .
OHH ! OHH !
SO . IT WAS
ELECTRO-CHEMICAL OR WHATEVER , RIGHT ?
AND HE MISSED IT .
THE WREN . THAT 'S GREAT .
THAT 'S FUCKIN ' GREAT .
[ ROLLS BODY OVER ]
ALL RIGHT .
IT 'S TIME TO REASSESS THIS PLACE .
I 'VE BEEN OVER IT AGAIN AND AGAIN .
WHY WOULD THEY THROW INNOCENT PEOPLE IN HERE ?
ARE WE BEING PUNISHED ?
I 'VE NEVER DONE ANYTHING TO DESERVE THIS .
FORGET ABOUT ALL THAT !
YOU CAN 'T SEE THE BIG PICTURE FROM IN HERE ,
SO DON 'T TRY . KEEP YOUR HEAD DOWN .
KEEP IT SIMPLE .
JUST LOOK AT WHAT 'S IN FRONT OF YOU .
THAT 'S WHAT HE SAID .
START WITH US .
WE GOT AN ESCAPE ARTIST AND A COP .
THERE 'S GOTTA BE A REASON FOR THAT .
YOU 'RE A DOCTOR , HOLLOWAY .
THAT GIVES YOU A FUNCTION ,
A REASON , RIGHT ?
NO . IT JUST MAKES ME GO , " WHY ME
AND NOT ONE OF THE OTHER 10 MILLION DOCTORS OUT THERE ? "
[ SIGHS ]
LEAVEN . WHAT ARE YOU ?
NOTHING .
I JUST GO TO SCHOOL .
I HANG OUT WITH MY FRIENDS .
WHAT ELSE ?
THERE IS NOTHING ELSE .
MY PARENTS ARE THESE PEOPLE . I LIVE WITH THEM .
I 'M BORING .
I THINK WE HAVE TO ASK THE BIG QUESTIONS .
WHAT DOES " IT " WANT ? WHAT IS " IT " THINKING ?
" ONE DOWN , 4 TO GO . "
[ LOW RUMBLING ]
WHY DON 'T YOU TELL US WHAT YOUR PURPOSE IS , WORTH ?
OFTEN WONDERED THAT MYSELF .
[ SIGHS ]
I 'M JUST A GUY .
I WORK IN AN OFFICE BUILDING
DOING OFFICE BUILDING STUFF .
I WASN 'T EXACTLY BURSTING WITH JOIE DE VIVRE
BEFORE I GOT HERE . LIFE JUST SUCKS IN GENERAL .
OH , I CAN 'T STAND THAT ATTITUDE .
' CAUSE HE 'S RIGHT .
WHAT 'S YOUR PURPOSE , QUENTIN ?
KIDS .
3 OF THEM .
I HAVEN 'T MADE MY PEACE YET .
I 'M GETTIN ' OUTTA HERE NO MATTER WHAT .
THAT 'S WHERE MY STRENGTH COMES FROM .
YOU PEOPLE FIND YOURS WHEREVER YOU GOT IT .
CHRIST 'S SAKE , WORTH , WHAT DO YOU LIVE FOR ?
DON 'T YOU HAVE A WIFE OR A GIRLFRIEND OR SOMETHING ?
NOPE . I GOT A PRETTY FINE COLLECTION OF PORNOGRAPHY .
OH , NICE . NICE .
I HAVEN 'T GOT ANYBODY , EITHER ,
BUT I 'M NOT GIVING UP . I AM PISSED OFF .
THEY CAME INTO OUR HOMES .
THEY STRIPPED US BARE !
THEY TOOK MY RINGS !
THEY TOOK - -
OH , MY AMETHYST !
[ RUMBLING ]
I WANT TO KNOW WHO 'S RESPONSIBLE .
Quentin : LEAVEN ?
YOUR GLASSES .
YOU DON 'T NEED THEM ?
THEY 'RE FOR READING .
WELL , THEY TOOK OFF HER JEWELRY ,
BUT THEY MUST 'VE PUT THESE ON YOU .
IF NOTHING 'S RANDOM ... WHY ARE THEY HERE ?
Quentin : LEAVEN . WHAT DO YOU DO IN SCHOOL ?
MATH .
Holloway : WHAT CAN THEY MEAN ?
SHH !
149 .
PRIME NUMBERS .
I CAN 'T BELIEVE I DIDN 'T SEE IT BEFORE .
Quentin : SEE WHAT ?
IT SEEMS LIKE IF ANY OF THESE NUMBERS
ARE A PRIME , THEN THEN ROOM IS TRAPPED .
OK .
UM ...
645 .
THAT 'S NOT PRIME .
372 .
NO .
649 .
RIGHT . 11 TIMES 59 .
THAT 'S NOT PRIME , EITHER .
SO THAT ROOM IS SAFE .
WAIT , WAIT , WAIT . HOW CAN YOU MAKE THAT ASSUMPTION
BASED ON ONE PRIME NUMBER TRAP ?
I 'M NOT . THE INCINERATOR THING WAS PRIME - - 0-8-3 .
THE MOLECULAR CHEMICAL THINGY HAD 137 .
THE ACID ROOM HAD 149 .
YOU REMEMBER ALL THAT IN YOUR HEAD ?
I HAVE A FACILITY FOR IT .
LEAVEN ...
YOU BEAUTIFUL BRAIN .
BOOT IT .
OK . OUTTA THE WAY .
Leaven : BRAINS BEFORE BEAUTY .
SAFE !
HA HA !
SAFE .
HA HA HA !
PRIME NUMBERS !
Echo : PRIME NUMBERS !
OHHH . HOW LONG HAVE WE BEEN IN HERE ?
Quentin : 9 OR 10 HOURS .
HOW DO YOU KNOW ?
5 O 'CLOCK SHADOW .
THE LAST THING I REMEMBER WAS SHAVING .
I GUESS I MISSED BREAKFAST ...
OR LUNCH ...
OR ... WHATEVER .
WELL , DON 'T WORRY .
I 'LL BE HOME IN TIME FOR DINNER .
[ SQUEALING ]
IF WE GET OUT , I 'LL MAKE YOU DINNER .
YOU GOT A DATE .
DOIN ' GOOD .
[ WHOOSHING ]
I NEED TO SMOKE !
I 'D SMOKE A BUTT OFF THE SIDEWALK .
HOLLOWAY . JUST REEL YOURSELF IN A BIT .
COME ON . WE 'RE MOVIN ' ALONG .
THINGS ARE LOOKIN ' UP .
OK , OK . YOU 'RE RIGHT . I QUIT SMOKING YEARS AGO .
[ GASPS ]
I JUST NEED TO BE OCCUPIED .
TALK . HAVE A CONVERSATION .
WHAT KIND OF DOCTOR ARE YOU , ANYWAY ?
UH ... OH , YOU KNOW , I 'M THE FREE KIND .
OK , CHITCHAT , CHITCHAT . UH ...
UH , TELL ME ABOUT YOUR RUG RATS .
OK . WE HAVE 3 BOYS - -
9 , 7 , AND 5 .
GOOD GOD .
POOR WOMAN .
THERE 'S NO WAY I 'D SURVIVE THAT .
YEAH , WELL ... SHE DIDN 'T , EITHER .
NO , SHE 'S NOT DEAD . WE 'RE JUST SEPARATED .
UH ...
I 'M SORRY .
I CAN 'T JUST SHOOT THE BREEZE .
THESE NUMBERS AREN 'T PRIME .
OK . CLEAR .
EXCUSE ME . SORRY .
YOU COULD TRY AND HELP ME OUT HERE , BUDDY .
NO , I COULDN 'T .
THIS ONE 'S TRAPPED , TOO .
WE HAVE TO BACKTRACK ?
NOT YET .
Holloway : OH , NO .
READ THEM TO ME .
Holloway : WHAT ARE YOU , HIS COATRACK ?
Leaven : OH , PLEASE .
[ BANG BANG ]
[ BANG ]
IT 'S STUCK .
[ SLIDING ]
AAAHHH ! LOOK OUT !
UNH !
[ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
THIS ROOM IS GREEN .
[ THUMP THUMP THUMP ]
HOLLOWAY .
HI THERE .
THIS ROOM IS GREEN .
Holloway : YES , IT IS .
I WANT TO GO BACK TO THE BLUE ROOM .
WHAT IS IT , SHOCK OR WHAT ?
I THINK HE 'S MENTALLY HANDICAPPED .
I LIKE THE BLUE ROOM .
JESUS CHRIST .
HE ALMOST BROKE MY NECK .
HEY THERE , ARE YOU ALL ALONE ?
YOU WANT TO HOLD MY HAND , HONEY ?
MMM ... BUTTER FIRST . THEN HONEY , KAZAN .
BUTTER FIRST , THEN HONEY .
HOW 'D HE SURVIVE ?
I WANT TO GO BACK TO THE BLUE ROOM .
THERE 'S LOTS OF BLUE ROOMS .
WE 'LL FIND YOU ANOTHER ONE REAL SOON .
Leaven : THIS IS JUST WAY TOO BIZARRE .
WELL , YOU JUST WORRY ABOUT YOUR NUMBERS THEN .
GO ON . I 'LL LOOK AFTER HIM .
SAFE , OBVIOUSLY ,
SINCE HE ALMOST FELL ON MY HEAD .
Holloway : SHALL WE GO FOR A WALK ...
KAZAN ?
YOU WANT TO GO FOR A WALK ?
[ WAILING ]
Holloway : UM ... QUENTIN ?
LET 'S NOT MAKE HIM DO THE CLIMBING THING RIGHT AWAY .
HOLLOWAY ...
HOLLOWAY .
Holloway : COULD THEY HAVE TAKEN US
ALL THE WAY TO NEW MEXICO ?
Quentin : WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT , HOLLOWAY ?
I 'M TALKING ABOUT WHERE DO YOU HIDE SOMETHING THIS BIG .
AT LEAST HE 'S GOOD FOR SOMETHING .
HEY , I 'M SORRY TO SHAKE YOUR FOUNDATIONS , QUENTIN ,
BUT YOU HAVE NO IDEA WHERE YOUR TAX DOLLARS GO .
FREE CLINIC DOCTORS ?
ONLY THE MILITARY INDUSTRIAL COMPLEX
COULD AFFORD TO BUILD SOMETHING THIS SIZE .
HOLLOWAY ...
WHAT IS THE MILITARY INDUSTRIAL COMPLEX ?
HAVE YOU EVER BEEN THERE ?
I 'M TELLING YOU , IT 'S NOT THAT COMPLEX .
HOW WOULD YOU KNOW , FROM WHERE YOU ARE ?
WHO DO YOU THINK THE ESTABLISHMENT IS ?
IT 'S JUST GUYS LIKE ME .
THEIR DESKS ARE BIGGER , BUT THEIR JOBS AREN 'T .
THEY DON 'T CONSPIRE . THEY BUY ... BOATS .
NO . THIS PLACE IS ...
REMEMBER SCARAMANGA ?
THE BAD GUY IN THE MAN WITH THE GOLDEN GUN .
YEAH .
IT 'S SOME RICH PSYCHO 'S ENTERTAINMENT .
HA HA HA !
IS THAT WHAT YOU THINK ?
CLEAR .
HA HA HA !
OK . YOU 'RE A COP .
SINGLE BULLET THEORY .
RIGHT ON .
[ CHOKING ]
[ WAILING ]
GAS !
HOLLOWAY , GET BACK HERE !
[ COUGHS , SWALLOWS ]
IT 'S OK .
I JUST SWALLOWED MY BUTTON .
[ KAZAN WAILING ]
I HATE THIS . I HATE THIS .
YOUR BOY 'S HAVING A CONNIPTION FIT IN THERE .
IT 'S LIKE CRAMMING WITHOUT COFFEE .
SHE NEEDS A BREAK .
SHE CAN DO IT .
THEY DON 'T LOOK PRIME TO ME .
IS THAT YOUR TWO-BITS WORTH , WORTH ?
FOR THAT IT 'S WORTH .
WELL ?
WELL , HE 'S RIGHT .
NOT PRIME .
STOP !
IN FRONT OF YOU !
WHAT IS IT ?
OW !
[ KAZAN WAILING ]
SHUT UP !
I DON 'T KNOW WHAT HAPPENED . IT WASN 'T PRIME .
QUENTIN , HOLD STILL .
[ KAZAN WAILING ]
SOMEBODY STOP THAT RACKET !
WORTH !
LEAVE THE BOOTS .
[ WAILING ]
AND SHUT THE FUCKING DOOR !
I HAD A FEELING ABOUT THAT FUCKIN ' GUY .
HE KNEW ABOUT THAT TRAP .
BUT THESE NUMBERS AREN 'T PRIME .
THEN YOUR NUMBER SYSTEM FAILED , BUT HE KNEW .
KNEW WHAT ? HOW WOULD HE KNOW ?
YOU 'RE THE PARANOID ONE . THINK ABOUT IT .
HIS ONLY FUNCTION SO FAR
HAS BEEN TO KICK US WHEN WE 'RE DOWN .
SO HE HAS A BAD ATTITUDE .
YOU SAYING THAT MAKES HIM A SPY ?
TRUST ME ON THIS .
IT 'S MY JOB TO READ PEOPLE LIKE AN X-RAY .
[ DOOR SLIDES OPEN ]
HE DOESN 'T LIKE RED ROOMS .
SO WHAT HAPPENED ?
YOU SAW WHAT HAPPENED .
QUENTIN !
I GUESS THE NUMBERS ARE MORE COMPLICATED THAN I THOUGHT .
MAYBE THEY MEAN NOTHING AT ALL .
Leaven : NO . IT MEANS THEY 'RE MORE INVOLVED .
THEY 'VE WORKED FOR US UP TO NOW , HAVEN 'T THEY ?
I JUST NEED SOME MORE TIME WITH THEM .
WELL , WE NEED TO REST ANYWAY .
WELL , THAT 'S HANDY
' CAUSE THERE 'S NOT A FUCK OF A LOT ELSE WE CAN DO .
ARE THEY TELLING YOU ANYTHING ?
THEY 'RE NOT TAROT CARDS .
DO YOU HAVE ANY IDEA HOW MANY VARIABLES I HAVE TO CONSIDER
BEFORE I CAN DECIPHER NUMBERS THIS SIZE ?
THEY DON 'T REVEAL THEMSELVES RIGHT AWAY .
THEY 'RE LIKE PEOPLE .
Leaven : OH , GROSS !
NO , NOT HERE , HONEY .
OVER IN THE CORNER .
[ URINATING ]
WHAT ? HE 'S JUST PEEING .
JESUS CHRIST .
THAT 'S EXCELLENT .
NOW IT TOTALLY REEKS IN HERE !
YOU FIND THIS ALL PRETTY FUNNY , DON 'T YOU ?
WHAT 'S YOUR FUCKING PROBLEM , WORTH ?
EVEN HOLLOWAY 'S HOLDING UP BETTER THAN YOU .
GET OVER THERE AND HELP HER WITH HIM .
THAT 'S YOUR JOB : BABY-SITTER .
JAWOHL , KOMMANDANT .
SOMEBODY HAS TO TAKE RESPONSIBILITY AROUND HERE .
AND THAT SOMEBODY HAS TO BE YOU .
NOT ALL OF US HAVE A LUXURY OF PLAYING NIHILIST .
NOT ALL OF US ARE CONCEITED ENOUGH TO PLAY HERO .
THIS IS A WILL TO LIVE .
EVERYBODY 'S GOT IT , WORTH , EVEN YOU .
ESPECIALLY YOU , HIDING BEHIND THAT CYNICAL FRONT .
A WILL TO LIVE .
THAT 'S THE WARM , COZY FEELING DEEP INSIDE ?
THANKS , QUENTIN . I 'M A NEW MAN .
OH , POOR WORTH .
NOBODY LOVES ME .
IF THAT 'S THE CHIP ON YOUR SHOULDER ,
WHY DID YOU LUG IT ALL THIS WAY ?
WHY DON 'T YOU JUST LIE DOWN AND DIE ?
DO IT .
SHOW US YOU HAVE SOME BACKBONE
AND JUMP IN THE SUSHI MACHINE .
BE A MAN .
THOUGHT SO .
FUCK YOU , QUENTIN .
I DON 'T WANNA DIE .
I 'M JUST BEING REALISTIC .
DO YOU THINK THEY 'D GO TO ALL THE TROUBLE TO BUILD THIS THING
IF WE COULD JUST WALK OUT ?
DO YOU THINK THEY WOULD 'VE LEFT US CLUES
AND LET US BEAT IT SO FAR IF THERE WASN 'T A WAY OUT ?
YOU THINK WE MATTER ? WE DON 'T .
PUT US OUT OF YOUR MISERY
SO WE CAN GET ON WITH GETTING OUT OF HERE .
OH , YOU 'RE NOT GETTING OUT OF HERE !
YES , WE ARE ! NO , YOU 'RE NOT .
YES , WE ARE !
THERE IS NO WAY OUT OF HERE !
GOTCHA .
HOW DO YOU KNOW THAT ?
ANSWER THE QUESTION , WORTH .
OH , GOD .
WHO ARE YOU ?
I 'M THE POISON .
I DESIGNED THE OUTER SHELL .
THE WHAT ?
THE SHELL . THE SARCOPHAGUS .
YOU BUILT THIS THING ?
NOT THIS PART . THE EXTERIOR .
I DON 'T KNOW ANYTHING ABOUT THE NUMBERS
OR ANYTHING ELSE IN HERE .
I WAS CONTRACTED TO DRAW PLANS FOR A HOLLOW SHELL .
A CUBE .
A CUBE ? WHY DIDN 'T YOU TELL US ?
FOR GOD SAKES , WORTH , YOU KNEW WHAT IT WAS .
NO .
WORTH ...
YOU 'RE LYING .
NOT AT FIRST .
Holloway : WHO 'S BEHIND IT ?
I DON 'T KNOW .
WHO HIRED YOU ?
I DIDN 'T ASK .
I NEVER EVEN LEFT MY OFFICE .
I TALKED ON THE PHONE TO SOME PEOPLE ,
OTHER GUYS LIKE ME ,
SPECIALISTS WORKING ON SMALL DETAILS .
NOBODY KNEW WHAT IT WAS .
NOBODY CARED .
BULLSHIT ! YOU KNEW FROM SQUARE ONE .
LOOK AT HIM .
HE 'S UP TO HIS EYEBALLS IN THIS THING .
NO , QUENTIN .
THAT 'S HOW THEY STAY HIDDEN .
YOU KEEP EVERYONE SEPARATED
SO THE LEFT HAND DOESN 'T KNOW WHAT THE RIGHT HAND IS DOING .
THE BRAIN NEVER COMES OUT IN THE OPEN .
WHOSE BRAIN ?
IT 'S ALL THE SAME MACHINE , RIGHT ?
THE PENTAGON ,
MULTINATIONAL CORPORATIONS ,
THE POLICE .
YOU DO ONE LITTLE JOB .
YOU BUILD A WIDGET IN SASKATOON ,
AND THE NEXT THING YOU KNOW ,
IT 'S 2 MILES UNDER THE DESERT ,
THE ESSENTIAL COMPONENT OF A DEATH MACHINE .
I WAS RIGHT ALL ALONG !
MY WHOLE LIFE , I KNEW IT !
I TOLD YOU , QUENTIN !
NOBODY 'S EVER GONNA CALL ME PARANOID AGAIN !
WE GOTTA GET OUT OF HERE
AND BLOW THE LID OFF THIS THING !
HOLLOWAY , YOU DON 'T GET IT .
THEN HELP ME , PLEASE . I NEED TO KNOW .
THIS MAY BE HARD FOR YOU TO UNDERSTAND ,
BUT THERE 'S NO CONSPIRACY .
NOBODY IS IN CHARGE .
IT 'S A HEADLESS BLUNDER
OPERATING UNDER THE ILLUSION OF A MASTER PLAN .
CAN YOU GRASP THAT ?
BIG BROTHER IS NOT WATCHING YOU .
WHAT KIND OF FUCKIN ' EXPLANATION IS THAT ?
IT 'S THE BEST YOU 'RE GONNA GET .
I LOOKED , AND THE ONLY CONCLUSION I CAN COME TO
IS THAT THERE IS NOBODY UP THERE .
SOMEBODY HAD TO SAY YES TO THIS THING .
WHAT THING ? ONLY WE KNOW WHAT IT IS .
WE HAVE NO IDEA WHAT IT IS .
WE KNOW MORE THAN ANYBODY ELSE .
I MEAN , SOMEBODY MIGHT 'VE KNOWN SOMETIME
BEFORE THEY GOT FIRED OR VOTED OUT OR SOLD IT .
BUT IF THIS PLACE EVER HAD A PURPOSE ,
THEN IT GOT MISCOMMUNICATED OR LOST IN THE SHUFFLE .
I MEAN , THIS IS AN ACCIDENT ,
A FORGOTTEN , PERPETUAL PUBLIC WORKS PROJECT .
YOU THINK ANYBODY WANTS TO ASK QUESTIONS ?
ALL THEY WANT IS A CLEAR CONSCIENCE
AND A FAT PAYCHECK .
I MEAN , I LEANED ON MY SHOVEL FOR MONTHS ON THIS ONE .
THIS WAS A GREAT JOB .
WHY PUT PEOPLE IN IT ?
BECAUSE IT 'S HERE .
YOU HAVE TO USE IT , OR YOU ADMIT IT 'S POINTLESS .
BUT IT ...
IT IS POINTLESS !
QUENTIN , THAT 'S MY POINT .
WHAT HAVE WE COME TO ?
IT 'S SO MUCH WORSE THAN I THOUGHT .
NOT REALLY .
JUST MORE PATHETIC .
YOU MAKE ME SICK , WORTH .
I MAKE ME SICK , TOO .
WE 'RE BOTH PART OF THE SYSTEM .
I DREW A BOX , YOU WALK A BEAT .
IT 'S LIKE YOU SAID , QUENTIN :
JUST KEEP YOUR HEAD DOWN , KEEP IT SIMPLE ,
JUST LOOK AT WHAT 'S IN FRONT OF YOU .
I MEAN , NOBODY WANTS TO SEE THE BIG PICTURE .
LIFE 'S TOO COMPLICATED .
I MEAN , LET 'S FACE IT .
THE REASON WE 'RE HERE IS THAT IT 'S OUT OF CONTROL .
THIS IS HOW WE RUIN THE WORLD ?
Leaven : WELL , DUH !
HAVE YOU BEEN ON GLUE ALL YOUR LIVES ?
I FELT GUILTY FOR RUINING THE WORLD
SINCE I WAS , LIKE , 7 .
GOD !
IF YOU NEED SOMEONE TO BLAME , THROW A ROCK !
WELL , I FEEL BETTER .
THAT 'S WHY YOU STAYED WITH US .
TO CONFESS .
STILL LOOKING FOR SOMEONE TO BUST , QUENTIN ?
Leaven : QUENTIN , STOP IT !
STOP IT !
WE NEED HIM .
WHAT FOR ?
HAVE YOU GONE ABSOLUTELY MAD ?
HE 'S THE ONLY ONE WHO KNOWS ANYTHING ABOUT THE PLACE .
WORTH .
HI .
SO THERE 'S THIS OUTER SHELL .
YEAH .
AND IT 'S A CUBE , RIGHT ? LIKE THIS ?
I ASSUME SO .
ARE THERE ANY DOORS ?
THIS ONE DOOR .
WHERE ?
WHEREVER THE DOOR GUY PUT IT .
6 GUESSES , AND IT 'S SEALED FROM THE OUTSIDE .
AND WHAT ARE THE DIMENSIONS OF THE OUTER SHELL ?
434 FEET SQUARE .
MAY I ?
COME ON , HONEY , SLIDE OVER .
14 BY 14 BY 14 .
THE INNER CUBE CAN 'T BE FLUSH TO THE SHELL WALL .
I KNOW THAT . THERE 'S A SPACE .
ONE CUBE ?
I DON 'T KNOW . IT MAKES SENSE .
OK .
WELL , THE BIGGEST THAT THE CUBE CAN BE , THEN ,
IS 26 ROOMS HIGH , 26 ROOMS ACROSS , SO ...
17,576 ROOMS .
17,576 ROOMS ?
OH , GOD .
THAT MAKES ME QUEASY .
DESCARTES !
LEAVEN , YOU ARE A GENIUS .
WHAT ? WHAT ?
CARTESIAN COORDINATES .
OF COURSE !
CODED CARTESIAN COORDINATES .
THEY 'RE USED IN GEOMETRY TO PLOT POINTS
ON A 3-DIMENSIONAL GRAPH .
IN ENGLISH .
SLOWER .
BONJOUR ?
THESE NUMBERS ARE MARKERS .
A GRID REFERENCE ,
LIKE LATITUDE AND LONGITUDE ON A MAP .
THE NUMBERS TELL US WHERE WE ARE INSIDE THE CUBE .
BUT WHERE ARE WE ?
IT WORKS !
OK , UM , ALL WE HAVE TO DO IS ADD THE NUMBERS TOGETHER .
" X " COORDINATE IS 19 .
" Y " IS ...
26 ROOMS .
SO THAT PLACES US ...
7 ROOMS FROM THE EDGE .
ALL RIGHT .
LET 'S GO .
JUST OUT OF CURIOSITY - -
I MEAN , DON 'T HIT ME AGAIN OR ANYTHING - -
BUT WHAT ARE YOU GONNA DO WHEN YOU GET THERE ?
MAYBE WE CAN GET THE DOOR OPEN .
HUH . RIGHT .
WHAT WE NEED TO DO
IS FIGURE OUT HOW TO GET AROUND THE TRAPS .
I 'M DEALING WITH THAT , HOLLOWAY .
I 'M LOOKING FOR PRACTICAL SOLUTIONS HERE .
WELL , YOU HAVEN 'T FOUND ANY YET .
WE CUT THE RISK
WITH THE NUMBERS AND THE BOOT .
WORTH WILL GO IN FIRST .
NO , HE WON 'T , QUENTIN . WE TAKE TURNS !
RELAX .
Quentin : ROOM FOR 2 IN THERE ?
WHAT 'S THE MATTER ?
THESE COORDINATES .
14 , 27 , 14 .
WHAT ABOUT ' EM ?
WELL , THEY DON 'T MAKE SENSE .
ASSUMING THE CUBE IS 26 ROOMS ACROSS ,
THERE CAN 'T BE A COORDINATE LARGER THAN 26 .
IF THIS WERE RIGHT ,
THEN WE WOULD BE OUTSIDE OF THE CUBE .
NO . NOT OUTSIDE OF THE CUBE .
OH . GUESS THAT MEANS WE 'RE NOT HAVING DINNER .
TRAP , TRAP , TRAP , TRAP , TRAP , TRAP , TRAP .
TRAP !
SOUND ACTIVATED .
BOO .
LOVELY .
HOW COME THE SOUND OF THE DOOR OPENING
DIDN 'T SET IT OFF ?
MUST BE RIGGED TO IGNORE IT .
SO THAT 'S IT .
THE EDGE IS SURROUNDED BY TRAPS .
WELL , I GUESS WE HAVE TO BACKTRACK
AND TRY SOMEWHERE ELSE .
WHO KNOWS HOW MANY DETOURS WE 'LL HAVE TO TAKE ?
I SAY WE CROSS THE BITCH .
RIGHT .
HOW MANY BOOTS DO WE HAVE LEFT , HOLLOWAY ?
GET IT OFF HIM .
WE KNOW HOW IT WORKS .
WE JUST HAVE TO BE QUIET .
THAT 'S PRETTY FUCKING QUIET .
I 'M GLAD YOU 'RE ON SIDE , WORTH ,
' CAUSE ... YOU 'RE UP .
Kazan : AH !
AND HE 'S NOT COMING .
OF COURSE HE IS .
NO WAY .
YOU 'RE NOT LEAVING HIM BEHIND .
HE 'S UNPREDICTABLE .
WHEN WE GET TO THE EDGE , WE CAN COME BACK FOR HIM ,
BUT HE 'LL GET SOMEBODY KILLED HERE !
AM I RIGHT ?
SHAME ON YOU .
WILL YOU LOOK AT YOURSELVES ?
WHAT HAVE YOU TURNED INTO ?
THEY MAY HAVE TAKEN OUR LIVES AWAY ,
BUT WE 'RE STILL HUMAN BEINGS .
THAT 'S ALL WE 'VE GOT LEFT .
WE 'LL COME BACK FOR HIM .
THAT 'S A LIE , AND YOU KNOW IT .
HMM ... HMM ... HMM ...
HE 'LL BE QUIET .
HMM ...
[ RUMBLING ]
[ CLICK ]
AH !
AAH !
YOU FUCKING FUCK !
ALL RIGHT , THAT 'S ENOUGH !
HE 'S A TRAP !
LET HIM GO RIGHT NOW !
LAW OF THE JUNGLE , HOLLOWAY .
HE 'S ENDANGERING THE PACK .
LET HIM GO , YOU NAZI !
WHAT 'D YOU CALL ME ?
QUENTIN , YOU LET THAT INNOCENT BOY GO .
YOU LISTEN TO ME , WOMAN .
EVERY DAY I MOP UP AFTER YOUR BLEEDING HEART .
THE ONLY REASON YOU EVEN EXIST
IS BECAUSE I KEEP YOU !
I KNOW YOUR TYPE :
NO KIDS ,
NO MAN TO FUCK YOU ,
SO YOU GO AROUND OUTRAGED ,
STICKING YOUR NOSE UP OTHER PEOPLE 'S ASSHOLES ,
SNIFFING THEIR BUSINESS !
YOU MISSED YOUR BOAT , HOLLOWAY .
YOU 'RE ALL DRIED UP INSIDE THERE , AREN 'T YOU ?
THAT 'S YOUR FUCKING PROBLEM .
HOW DARE YOU SAY THAT TO HER .
YOU DON 'T KNOW HER , QUENTIN .
NONE OF US KNOW EACH OTHER HERE .
OH , I DO .
NO , YOU DON 'T !
NO WONDER YOUR WIFE LEFT YOU .
ALL THAT BOTTLED UP ANGER .
AND A THING FOR YOUNG GIRLS .
OHH !
GOD HELP YOU , QUENTIN .
DID YOU SMACK YOUR KIDS AROUND , TOO ?
IS ANYBODY BESIDES ME
INTERESTED IN WHAT 'S ON THE OTHER SIDE OF THAT DOOR ?
OPEN IT .
DOOR NUMBER 6 ,
NOT NUMBER 1 , DOOR NUMBER 2 ?
OPEN THE FUCKING THING .
SUNSHINE .
NIGHTTIME .
MY OLD FRIEND THE SHELL .
IT 'S THERE .
MORNING !
[ ECHO ] MORNING ... MORNING ...
HANG ON TO ME .
CAN 'T SEE SHIT .
NOTHING TO HANG ON TO .
WE GOTTA TRY SOMETHING .
WE GOTTA SEE IF THE DOOR 'S OVER THERE .
SOMEONE HAS TO SWING OVER THERE
AND TAKE A LOOK .
Worth : SWING ?
WE MAKE A ROPE OUT OF CLOTHES .
TAKE ' EM OFF .
I 'LL TIE IT AROUND MYSELF .
YEAH , YOU 'RE GONNA GO .
YOU WEIGH , LIKE , 500 POUNDS .
IT 'LL SNAP IN 2 SECONDS .
I 'M THE LIGHTEST .
FORGET IT .
I 'LL GO .
I 'M GOING , HOLLOWAY .
SHE 'S RIGHT , QUENTIN . YOU 'RE TOO HEAVY .
I 'M THE LIGHTEST AFTER LEAVEN .
ANYWAYS , IT 'S MY TURN .
HOW LONG DID YOU KNOW
PEOPLE WERE BEING PUT IN HERE ?
COUPLE MONTHS .
THAT 'S NOT LONG ,
IF YOU CONSIDER YOUR WHOLE LIFE .
I AM .
YOU OPENED MY EYES , WORTH . THAT 'S SOMETHING .
DAVID .
HELEN .
YOU 'RE SUCH A HELEN .
THAT 'S AS FAR AS YOU GO !
THERE 'S NOTHING DOWN HERE !
HOLD TIGHT .
I 'LL TRY SWINGING OVER THERE .
BRACE YOURSELVES . I 'M GONNA TRY AGAIN .
OK .
ONE MORE TIME .
HURRY !
YOU 'RE GETTING HEAVY .
[ RUMBLING ]
AAH !
WHAT THE HELL 'S GOING ON ? !
Quentin : GET UP HERE NOW !
[ CHUCKLES ]
Worth : QUENTIN !
Leaven : HAVE YOU GOT HER ?
WHAT 'S GOING ON ?
QUENTIN , IS SHE OK ?
AAH !
SHE , UH ...
SLIPPED .
HOLLOWAY ?
[ WAILING ]
SHH . COME ON , KAZAN .
[ CONTINUES WAILING ]
KAZAN , WILL YOU PLEASE STOP DOING THAT ?
LEAVEN ...
YOU GOTTA BE STRONG , SWEETHEART .
DON 'T EVEN TALK TO ME .
WE GOTTA GET DOWN TO THE BOTTOM .
IT 'LL BE EASIER TO GET ONTO THE SHELL FROM THERE .
IT 'S A LONG FUCKIN ' WAY WITH ONLY ONE BOOT ,
BUT WE GOTTA DO IT BEFORE WE GET TOO WEAK .
GOTTA KEEP CRACKING THE NUMBERS , LEAVEN .
I CAN 'T THINK ANYMORE .
SURE YOU CAN .
IT 'S YOUR GIFT .
IT 'S NOT A GIFT .
IT 'S JUST A BRAIN .
LET HER SLEEP FOR A WHILE .
WE HAVEN 'T SLEPT IN FUCK KNOWS HOW LONG .
ALL RIGHT .
ONE HOUR .
HOW THE FUCK ARE YOU GONNA KNOW
HOW LONG AN HOUR IS ?
AN HOUR IS AS LONG AS I SAY .
[ GROGGY ] WHAT ARE YOU DOING ?
WE HAVE TO MAKE IT DOWN TO THE BOTTOM .
IT 'LL BE QUIET THERE . YOU CAN CONCENTRATE .
YOU JUST WANNA LEAVE THEM ?
THEY 'RE TRAPS , LEAVEN .
WE ARE THE KEY . I 'LL GET US DOWN THERE .
YOU THINK US OUT . BELIEVE IN ME .
TRY AND SEE WHAT I SEE , HOW MY MIND WORKS - -
THE FLASH WHEN I LOOK INTO SOMEONE 'S HEAD ,
LIKE A FUCKING X-RAY .
I LOOKED THROUGH THE WALLS .
I DREAMED HIM AT HIS DESK ,
DESIGNING EVERYTHING .
HE CAN 'T LET YOU SOLVE THE PUZZLE , SEE ,
BECAUSE THERE IS A PURPOSE .
WE ARE THE PURPOSE .
THE CUBE ... IS US .
QUENTIN ...
WE FIT ... LIKE NUMBERS .
A MAN AND A WOMAN .
2 HALVES OF THE EQUATION .
I TAKE YOU DOWN ...
THE PERFECT KEY .
I SLIP YOU IN THE LOCK .
AAH !
LEAVEN ...
IT 'S TIME TO GO DOWN .
[ WHINING AND SOBBING ]
AAH !
[ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
GET AWAY FROM HER .
LEAVEN ...
THEY 'RE FUCKING SPIES - -
HIM , THE RETARD .
HOLLOWAY HAD OUTSIDE INFORMATION
ABOUT MY FAMILY ,
BUT SHE SLIPPED UP , DIDN 'T SHE ?
SHE CROSSED THE LINE .
YOU DROPPED HER .
JUST GO , QUENTIN .
GIVE US THE BOOT , YOU PIG !
AAH !
YOU DON 'T WANT THE BOOT .
[ WORTH MOANS ]
YOU WANT TO COME WITH US , WORTH ?
DOWN THE HATCH .
AAH !
[ GASPS ]
[ WORTH LAUGHING ]
WHAT THE FUCK 'S WITH HIM ?
HA HA HA HA HA HA .
HA HA HA HA HA .
HOW DID ...
HA HA HA . IT 'S - - IT 'S - - IT 'S THE WREN .
HA HA . THE OLD WRENSTER .
HOW COULD ...
HA HA HA . WE 'VE BEEN GOING IN CIRCLES .
THAT CAN 'T BE .
WHERE ARE WE ?
I DON 'T KNOW .
[ DOOR SLIDES OPEN ]
WHERE ARE WE ?
YOU FIGURE IT OUT .
YOU HAVEN 'T DONE ANYTHING .
ALL YOU DID WAS FREAK OUT , YOU ... MURDERER !
[ CRYING ]
HA HA HA HA .
I GUESS YOU WERE RIGHT , WORTH .
THERE IS NO WAY OUT OF HERE .
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ CRYING ]
GET AWAY FROM ME .
WASN 'T RENNES KILLED IN THAT ROOM ?
HOW COME THERE 'S NOTHING OUT THERE ?
IT 'S THE EDGE .
BUT WE WEREN 'T AT THE EDGE BEFORE .
WHERE 'S THE ROOM THAT KILLED RENNES ?
FUCK OFF !
OH , THAT WAS GOOD .
WHAT DIFFERENCE DOES IT MAKE ?
WE 'RE DEAD , ANYWAYS .
HEY ! LISTEN TO WHAT I 'M SAYING .
THERE WAS A ROOM THERE BEFORE .
WE HAVEN 'T BEEN MOVING IN CIRCLES .
THE ROOMS HAVE .
OF COURSE .
THE ROOMS ?
THAT EXPLAINS THE THUNDER AND THE SHAKING .
WE 'VE BEEN SHIFTING THE WHOLE TIME .
IT 'S THE ONLY LOGICAL EXPLANATION .
I AM SUCH AN IDIOT .
WHAT ARE YOU ONTO , LEAVEN ?
GIMME A MINUTE .
OK , THE NUMBERS ARE MARKERS ,
POINTS ON A MAP , RIGHT ?
RIGHT .
THEN HOW DO YOU MAP A POINT
THAT KEEPS MOVING ?
PERMUTATIONS .
PERMU WHAT ?
PERMUTATIONS . A LIST OF ALL THE COORDINATES
THAT THE ROOM PASSES THROUGH .
LIKE A MAP THAT TELLS YOU
WHERE THE ROOM STARTS ,
HOW MANY TIMES IT MOVES ,
AND WHERE IT MOVES TO .
A NUMBER TELLS YOU ALL THAT ?
I DON 'T KNOW .
SEE , I 'VE ONLY BEEN LOOKING
AT ONE POINT ON THE MAP ,
WHICH IS PROBABLY THE STARTING POSITION .
ALL I SAW WAS WHAT THE CUBE LOOKED LIKE
BEFORE IT STARTED TO MOVE .
OK , SO IT 'S MOVING .
HOW DO WE GET OUT ?
27 .
I KNOW WHERE THE EXIT IS .
WHERE ?
STAY AWAY FROM ME .
BACK OFF , QUENTIN .
I JUST WANNA KNOW .
DON 'T YOU WANNA KNOW ?
YOU REMEMBER THAT ROOM WE PASSED THROUGH BEFORE ,
THE ONE WITH THE COORDINATE LARGER THAN 26 ?
WHAT ABOUT IT ?
THAT COORDINATE PLACED THE ROOM
OUTSIDE THE CUBE .
A BRIDGE .
RIGHT . BUT ONLY IN ITS ORIGINAL POSITION .
WHAT ARE YOU TALKING ABOUT ?
LOOK , THE ROOM STARTS OFF AS A BRIDGE ,
THEN IT MOVES ITS WAY THROUGH THE MAZE ,
WHICH IS WHERE WE RAN INTO IT ,
BUT AT SOME POINT ,
IT MUST RETURN TO ITS ORIGINAL POSITION .
SO THE BRIDGE IS ONLY A BRIDGE ...
FOR A SHORT PERIOD OF TIME .
THIS THING IS LIKE A GIANT COMBINATION LOCK .
WHEN THE ROOMS ARE IN THEIR STARTING POSITION ,
THE LOCK IS OPEN .
BUT WHEN THEY MOVE OUT OF ALIGNMENT ,
THE LOCK CLOSES .
WITH A STRUCTURE THIS SIZE ,
IT MUST TAKE DAYS FOR THE ROOMS TO COMPLETE A FULL CYCLE .
SO WHEN DOES IT OPEN ?
DON 'T .
TO FIND THE ORIGINAL COORDINATES ,
THE NUMBERS ARE ADDED TOGETHER .
TO FIND THE PERMUTATIONS ,
THEY 'RE SUBTRACTED FROM ONE ANOTHER .
THAT 'S IT .
THIS ROOM MOVES TO ZERO , ONE ,
AND NEGATIVE ONE ON THE X-AXIS .
2 , 5 , AND NEGATIVE 7 ON Y.
AND ONE , NEGATIVE ONE , AND ZERO ON ZED .
WHAT DOES THAT MEAN ?
YOU SUCK AT MATH ?
OK , I NEED THE ROOM NUMBERS AROUND US AS A REFERENCE POINT .
8-9-7 .
[ DOOR SLIDES OPEN ]
5-6-7 , 8-9-8 .
OK ? YES .
AND 5-4-5 . DID YOU GET THAT ?
7-7-8 .
THAT 'S ENOUGH .
X IS 17 , Y IS 25 , AND ZED IS 14 .
WHICH MEANS THIS ROOM MAKES 2 MORE MOVES
BEFORE RETURNING TO ITS ORIGINAL POSITION .
DO WE HAVE TIME ?
MAYBE .
THEN LET 'S GO .
CAN YOU WORK THE TRAPS FOR THIS SYSTEM ?
FUCK THE TRAPS . LET 'S GET TO THE BRIDGE .
YOU THREW OUT OUR LAST BOOT , YOU FUCKING IDIOT .
TECHNICALLY , I CAN IDENTIFY THE TRAPS .
TECHNICALLY ?
FIRST , I THOUGHT THAT THEY WERE IDENTIFIED BY PRIME NUMBERS ,
BUT THEY 'RE NOT .
THEY 'RE IDENTIFIED BY NUMBERS THAT ARE THE POWER OF A PRIME .
OK , SO ?
CAN YOU CALCULATE THAT ?
THE NUMBERS ARE HUGE .
BUT YOU CAN , RIGHT ? SHE CAN .
I 'D HAVE TO CALCULATE THE NUMBER OF FACTORS IN EACH SET .
MAYBE IF I HAD A COMPUTER .
YOU DON 'T NEED A COMPUTER .
YES , I DO ! FIGURE IT OUT .
I CAN 'T !
I 'M NOT DYING IN A FUCKING RAT MAZE !
LOOK , NOBODY IN THE WHOLE WORLD
COULD DO IT MENTALLY .
LOOK AT THE NUMBERS .
567 , 898 , 545 .
THERE 'S NO WAY I CAN FACTOR THAT .
I CAN 'T EVEN START ON 567 .
IT 'S ASTRONOMICAL !
2 .
ASTRONOMICAL .
WHAT DID YOU SAY ?
BEFORE THAT .
FACTORS .
HOW MANY FACTORS , KAZAN ,
OF 567 ?
2 .
WHAT , ARE YOU FUCKING KIDDING ?
KAZAN , HOW MANY FACTORS DOES 30 HAVE ?
3 .
HOW ABOUT 7 ?
ONE . GUMDROP .
I DON 'T HAVE ANY GUMDROPS .
GUMDROP .
KAZAN ...
I 'LL GIVE YA A WHOLE BOX OF GUMDROPS FOR EACH ANSWER .
GUMDROPS COME IN BAGS .
OK , YOU WANT ' EM IN BAGS , YOU GOT ' EM IN BAGS .
I DON 'T LIKE THE RED ONES .
[ DOOR SLIDES OPEN ]
8-9-8 .
2 .
5-4-5 .
HE 'S GIVING US THE FACTORS .
ASTRONOMICAL .
YOU 'RE TELLING ME
TELETHON BOY IS A GENIUS ?
BY THOSE NUMBERS , THE ROOM SHOULD BE SAFE .
ONLY ONE WAY TO FIND OUT .
DON 'T !
AAH !
SAFE .
KAZAN ...
MY MAN .
WHAT 'S THE NUMBER , BUDDY BOY ?
HEY !
RIGHT HERE . LOOK HERE !
MAKE HIM DO IT .
KAZAN , WE 'RE GONNA DO SOME NUMBERS NOW , OK ?
WE LIKE TO DO NUMBERS , RIGHT ?
PRIME NUMBERS .
THAT 'S RIGHT .
CAN YOU TELL ME THE FACTOR OF 6-5-6 ?
2 .
7-7-9 ?
4-6-2 ?
3 . CLEAR .
MOVE .
COME ON . COME ON , LET 'S GO .
YOU , TOO , WORTH .
Quentin : MOVE YOUR SCRAWNY ASS , WORTH .
I 'M NOT THROUGH WITH YOU YET .
LEAVEN , OPEN THAT DOOR .
GET EINSTEIN WORKIN ' ON THE NUMBERS .
OH , JEEZ .
GO ! WORTH ...
HURRY !
LEAVEN .
5-6-3 ?
PLEASE , KAZAN . 5-6-3 .
YOU FUCKERS . YOU 'RE DEAD .
2 . CLEAR .
ONE .
TRAPPED .
CHECK THE FLOOR .
IS HE DEAD ?
Quentin : AAH !
NOT QUITE .
NOT EVEN CLOSE !
WORTH , I 'M GETTING OUT OF HERE ,
AND I 'LL FEED YOU TO A FUCKING TRAP
ON THE WAY !
WHERE IS HE ? !
COME HERE .
I SAID COME HERE RIGHT NOW-W-W-W !
Worth : GOTCHA .
THAT WAY .
- 2 . - CLEAR .
- 4 . - CLEAR .
WHOA .
Leaven : WHOA .
[ CRASH ]
GUESS THAT PROVES OUR THEORY . NUMBERS .
4 . 2 .
3 . CLEAR .
[ RUMBLING ]
KAZAN ! KAZAN !
[ KAZAN WAILING ]
LISTEN .
HE HASN 'T MOVED FAR .
I 'LL GO FIND HIM .
WHAT DO YOU THINK ?
YOU DON 'T HAVE A LOT OF LIVES LEFT .
AAH .
[ KAZAN WAILS ]
[ DOOR SLIDES OPEN ]
KAZAN .
I ... DIDN 'T ... MOVE .
YEAH , GOOD , BUT YOU 'RE GONNA HAVE TO CLIMB UP HERE , OK ?
I DON 'T ... LIKE THAT .
14 ...
26 ...
14 .
WORTH , GET BACK HERE RIGHT NOW !
5 BAGS OF GUMDROPS .
27 BAGS TOTAL .
27 BAGS . DEAL .
WORTH , THIS ROOM 'S NEXT MOVE TAKES IT TO THE BRIDGE !
WE 'RE COMING !
OVER HERE .
MOVE IT !
WE DON 'T HAVE MUCH TIME . COME ON .
[ RUMBLING ]
AAH ! AAH ! AAH !
[ THUD ]
WORTH .
UNH .
THIS BETTER BE IT .
IT SHOULD BE .
WHERE ?
OH , WELL .
[ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
GIVE IT A MINUTE . BE PATIENT .
SO , GUESS WHAT .
NO .
THIS IS THE ROOM WE STARTED IN .
I WAS RIGHT .
WE SHOULD NEVER HAVE MOVED IN THE FIRST PLACE .
[ CHUCKLES ]
[ RUMBLING ]
[ THUD ]
THE BRIDGE .
RED .
Leaven : KAZAN ...
4 . 2 .
4 .
CLEAR .
[ DOOR SLIDES SHUT ]
[ SOBS ]
WORTH .
GO AHEAD .
WHAT ARE YOU DOING ? YOU CAN 'T QUIT NOW .
IT 'S NOT YOUR FAULT !
I HAVE NOTHING ... TO LIVE FOR OUT THERE .
WHAT IS OUT THERE ?
Worth : BOUNDLESS HUMAN STUPIDITY .
[ DOOR SLIDES OPEN ]
I CAN LIVE WITH THAT .
[ GASPS ]
[ GASPING FOR AIR ]
AAH !
KAZAN , GET OUT THROUGH THE DOOR !
[ WAILING ]
RED , KAZAN .
AAH !
[ THUD ]
CAPTIONING MADE POSSIBLE BY TRIMARK HOME VIDEO
CAPTIONING PERFORMED BY THE NATIONAL CAPTIONING INSTITUTE , INC .